<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Historical Site Wiki</string>
    <string name="title_placeholder">Title</string>
    <string name="location_placeholder">Locations</string>
    <string name="subtitle_detail_text">Detail</string>
    <string name="tv_credit">Thank you for downloading this app. \n \nRegards, \nTeam Two Players
    \n \nReferences: \nWikipedia \n \nPhoto : \n \nBy Daniel Schwen - Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=7647000
    \n \nBy Nina - Own work, CC BY 2.5, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=282496
    \n \nBy Arild Vågen - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=24932378
    \n \nBy Martin St-Amant (S23678) - Own work, CC BY-SA 3.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=8450312
    \n \nBy garethwiscombe - https://www.flickr.com/photos/garethwiscombe/1071477228/in/photostream/, CC BY 2.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=13278936
    </string>

    <string-array name="detail_title">
        <item>The Alhambra is a palace and fortress complex located in Granada,
        Andalusia, Spain. It was originally constructed as a small fortress in AD 889 on the remains
        of Roman fortifications, and then largely ignored until its ruins were renovated and rebuilt
        in the mid-13th century by the Nasrid emir Mohammed ben Al-Ahmar of the Emirate of Granada,
        who built its current palace and walls. \n \nIt was converted into a royal palace in 1333 by Yusuf I,
        Sultan of Granada.After the conclusion of the Christian Reconquista in 1492, the site became
        the Royal Court of Ferdinand and Isabella (where Christopher Columbus received royal endorsement
        for his expedition), and the palaces were partially altered in the Renaissance style. \n \nIn 1526 Charles I &amp; V commissioned a new Renaissance palace better befitting the Holy Roman Emperor
        in the revolutionary Mannerist style influenced by humanist philosophy in direct juxtaposition with
        the Nasrid Andalusian architecture, but it was ultimately never completed due to Morisco rebellions
        in Granada.</item>

        <item>Angkor Wat is a temple complex in Cambodia and one of the largest
        religious monuments in the world, on a site measuring 162.6 hectares. Originally constructed as a
        Hindu temple dedicated to the god Vishnu for the Khmer Empire, it was gradually transformed into a
        Buddhist temple towards the end of the 12th century. \n \nIt was built by the Khmer King Suryavarman II
        in the early 12th century in Yasodharapura, the capital of the Khmer Empire, as his state temple
        and eventual mausoleum. Breaking from the Shaiva tradition of previous kings, Angkor Wat was instead
        dedicated to Vishnu. As the best-preserved temple at the site, it is the only one to have remained
        a significant religious centre since its foundation. \n \nThe temple is at the top of the high classical
        style of Khmer architecture. It has become a symbol of Cambodia, appearing on its national flag,
        and it is the country\'s prime attraction for visitors.</item>

        <item>Chichen Itza was a large pre-Columbian city built by the Maya
        people of the Terminal Classic period. The archaeological site is located in Tinúm Municipality,
        Yucatán State, Mexico. Chichen Itza was a major focal point in the Northern Maya Lowlands from the
        Late Classic (c. AD 600–900) through the Terminal Classic (c. AD 800–900) and into the early portion
        of the Postclassic period (c. AD 900–1200). \n \nThe site exhibits a multitude of architectural styles,
        reminiscent of styles seen in central Mexico and of the Puuc and Chenes styles of the Northern Maya
        lowlands. \n \nThe presence of central Mexican styles was once thought to have been representative of
        direct migration or even conquest from central Mexico, but most contemporary interpretations view
        the presence of these non-Maya styles more as the result of cultural diffusion.</item>

        <item>The Great Pyramid of Giza (also known as the Pyramid of
        Khufu or the Pyramid of Cheops) is the oldest and largest of the three pyramids in the Giza pyramid
        complex bordering present-day El Giza, Egypt. It is the oldest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World,
        and the only one to remain largely intact. Based on a mark in an interior chamber naming the work gang and a reference to the fourth dynasty
        Egyptian Pharaoh Khufu, Egyptologists believe that the pyramid was built as a tomb over a 10- to
        20-year period concluding around 2560 BC. \n \nInitially at 146.5 metres (481 feet), the Great Pyramid
        was the tallest man-made structure in the world for more than 3,800 years. Originally, the Great
        Pyramid was covered by limestone casing stones that formed a smooth outer surface; what is seen
        today is the underlying core structure. Some of the casing stones that once covered the structure
        can still be seen around the base. \n \nThere have been varying scientific and alternative theories about
        the Great Pyramid\'s construction techniques. Most accepted construction hypotheses are based on the
        idea that it was built by moving huge stones from a quarry and dragging and lifting them into place.</item>
        >

        <item>Hagia Sophia is the former Greek Orthodox Christian patriarchal
        cathedral, later an Ottoman imperial mosque and now a museum (Ayasofya Müzesi) in Istanbul, Turkey.
        Built in 537 AD at the beginning of the Middle Ages, it was famous in particular for its massive dome.
        It was the world\'s largest building and an engineering marvel of its time. \n \nIt is considered the epitome
        of Byzantine architecture and is said to have "changed the history of architecture".
        The Hagia Sophia construction consists of mostly masonry. The structure is composed of brick and
        mortar joint that are 1.5 times the width of the bricks. \n \nThe mortar joints are composed of a
        combination of sand and minute ceramic pieces displaced very evenly throughout the mortar joints.
        This combination of sand and ceramic pieces could be considered to be the equivalent of modern
        concrete at the time.</item>>

        <item>Machu Picchu is a 15th-century Inca citadel, located in the Eastern
        Cordillera of southern Peru, on a mountain ridge 2,430 metres (7,970 ft) above sea level. It is located
        in the Cusco Region, Urubamba Province, Machupicchu District in Peru, above the Sacred Valley, which is
        80 kilometres (50 mi) northwest of Cuzco and through which the Urubamba River flows, which cuts through
        the Cordillera and originates a canyon with a tropical mountain climate. \n \nMost archaeologists believe that Machu Picchu was constructed as an estate for the Inca emperor
        Pachacuti (1438–1472). Often mistakenly referred to as the "Lost City of the Incas" (a title more
        accurately applied to Vilcabamba), it is the most familiar icon of Inca civilization. The Incas built
        the estate around 1450 but abandoned it a century later at the time of the Spanish Conquest. \n \nAlthough
        known locally, it was not known to the Spanish during the colonial period and remained unknown to the
        outside world until American historian Hiram Bingham brought it to international attention in 1911.</item>

        <item>Petra, originally known to its inhabitants as Raqmu, is a historical
        and archaeological city in southern Jordan. Petra lies on the slope of Jabal Al-Madbah in a basin
        among the mountains which form the eastern flank of the Arabah valley that runs from the Dead Sea
        to the Gulf of Aqaba. \n \nPetra is believed to have been settled as early as 9,000 BC, and it was possibly
        established in the 4th century BC as the capital city of the Nabataean Kingdom. The Nabataeans were
        nomadic Arabs who invested in Petra\'s proximity to the trade routes by establishing it as a major
        regional trading hub. \n \nThe trading business gained the Nabataeans considerable revenue and Petra became the focus of their
        wealth. The earliest historical reference to Petra was an attack to the city ordered by Antigonus
        I in 312 BC recorded by various Greek historians. The Nabataeans were, unlike their enemies, accustomed
        to living in the barren deserts, and were able to repel attacks by utilizing the area\'s mountainous
        terrain. They were particularly skillful in harvesting rainwater, agriculture and stone carving. \n \nPetra
        flourished in the 1st century AD when its famous Khazneh structure – believed to be the mausoleum of
        Nabataean King Aretas IV – was constructed, and its population peaked at an estimated 20,000 inhabitants.</item>
        >

        <item>Stonehenge is a prehistoric monument in Wiltshire, England,
        two miles (3 km) west of Amesbury. It consists of a ring of standing stones, with each standing
        stone around 13 feet (4.0 m) high, seven feet (2.1 m) wide and weighing around 25 tons. \n \nThe stones
        are set within earthworks in the middle of the most dense complex of Neolithic and Bronze Age
        monuments in England, including several hundred burial mounds. Archaeologists believe it was constructed
        from 3000 BC to 2000 BC. \n \nThe surrounding circular earth bank and ditch, which constitute the earliest
        phase of the monument, have been dated to about 3100 BC. Radiocarbon dating suggests that the first bluestones were raised between 2400
        and 2200 BC, although they may have been at the site as early as 3000 BC. \n \nOne of the most famous landmarks in the United Kingdom, Stonehenge is regarded as a British cultural
        icon. It has been a legally protected Scheduled Ancient Monument since 1882 when legislation to
        protect historic monuments was first successfully introduced in Britain. The site and its surroundings
        were added to UNESCOs list of World Heritage Sites in 1986. \n \nStonehenge is owned by the Crown and
        managed by English Heritage; the surrounding land is owned by the National Trust.</item>>

        <item>The Taj Mahal, meaning "Crown of the Palaces") is an ivory-white
        marble mausoleum on the south bank of the Yamuna river in the Indian city of Agra. It was commissioned
        in 1632 by the Mughal emperor, Shah Jahan (reigned from 1628 to 1658), to house the tomb of his
        favourite wife, Mumtaz Mahal. It also houses the tomb of Shah Jahan, the builder. The tomb is the
        centerpiece of a 17-hectare (42-acre) complex, which includes a mosque and a guest house, and is
        set in formal gardens bounded on three sides by a crenellated wall. \n \nConstruction of the mausoleum was essentially completed in 1643 but work continued on other phases
        of the project for another 10 years. The Taj Mahal complex is believed to have been completed in
        its entirety in 1653 at a cost estimated at the time to be around 32 million rupees, which in 2015
        would be approximately 52.8 billion rupees (U.S. $827 million). \n \nThe construction project employed
        some 20,000 artisans under the guidance of a board of architects led by the court architect to the
        emperor, Ustad Ahmad Lahauri.</item>>

        <item>Tikal is the ruin of an ancient city, which was likely to have been
        called Yax Mutal, found in a rainforest in Guatemala. It is one of the largest archaeological
        sites and urban centers of the pre-Columbian Maya civilization. It is located in the archaeological
        region of the Petén Basin in what is now northern Guatemala. Situated in the department of El Petén,
        the site is part of Guatemala\'s Tikal National Park and in 1979 it was declared a UNESCO World
        Heritage Site. \n \nTikal was the capital of a conquest state that became one of the most powerful kingdoms of the
        ancient Maya. Though monumental architecture at the site dates back as far as the 4th century BC,
        Tikal reached its apogee during the Classic Period, c. 200 to 900 AD. During this time, the city
        dominated much of the Maya region politically, economically, and militarily, while interacting
        with areas throughout Mesoamerica such as the great metropolis of Teotihuacan in the distant Valley
        of Mexico. \n \nThere is evidence that Tikal was conquered by Teotihuacan in the 4th century CE. Following
        the end of the Late Classic Period, no new major monuments were built at Tikal and there is evidence
        that elite palaces were burned. These events were coupled with a gradual population decline, culminating
        with the site’s abandonment by the end of the 10th century.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="site_titles">
        <item>Alhambra</item>
        <item>Angkor Wat</item>
        <item>Chichen Itza</item>
        <item>Great Pyramida of Giza</item>
        <item>Hagia Sophia</item>
        <item>Machu Picchu</item>
        <item>Petra</item>
        <item>Stonehenge</item>
        <item>Taj Mahal</item>
        <item>Tikal</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="site_location">
        <item>Location : Granada, Andalusia, Spain</item>
        <item>Location : Angkor, Siem Reap, Cambodia</item>
        <item>Location : Yucatan, Mexico</item>
        <item>Location : Egypt</item>
        <item>Location : Istanbul (historically Constantinople), Turkey</item>
        <item>Location : Cusco  Region, Peru</item>
        <item>Location : Maan Governorate, Jordan</item>
        <item>Location : Wiltshire, England</item>
        <item>Location : Agra, Uttar Pradesh, India</item>
        <item>Location : Flores, Petén Department, Guatemala</item>
    </string-array>

    <array name="site_images">
        <item>@drawable/img_alhambra</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_angkorwat</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_chicenitza</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_greatpyramidofgiza</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_hagiasophia</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_machupicchu</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_petra</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_stonehenge</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_tajmahal</item>
        <item>@drawable/img_tikal</item>
    </array>
</resources>
